

profile

Results-oriented iOS developer and designer that's been building iOS apps for over 4 years. I build software for people, and make it my goal to implement apps with a great user experience complimented with an inspiring user interface. I understand the importance of writing highly readable and maintainable code when working in teams or alone. I relentlessly push myself to learn and grow as fast as this industry changes by adopting new technologies and breaking out of my comfort zone. I have significant experience building apps from the ground up.

technologies and skills

Primary languages: Swift 1.2, Objective-C, Ruby, HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL

Technologies: Rails, Parse, Heroku, JSON, XML, CocoaPods, TestFlight, HockeyApp

Development: XCode, Sublime Text, Trello, SourceTree

Design software: Sketch App, Photoshop

experience

2015-2015 **Fitter** London, United Kingdom

Founder and iOS developer

- Designed and built the Fitter iOS application in Swift and Objective-C.
- App allows users to book workouts from boutique studios in two taps, along with tag and location based search, booking management and displaying weekly promotions.
- Integrates with a Rails REST API, with local caching implemented with Realm.io
- Created a guest checkout, allowing users to buy without having an account.
- Apple Pay launch partner; one of the first dozen apps to implement Apple Pay in the UK
- Featured on the front page of the Apple App Store.

2014-2015 HouseQuest London, United Kingdom

Founder and iOS developer

- Participated in the highly competitive EF startup accelerator programme.
- Designed and built a real-time, fully available property search application. Users can join groups and receive properties via push notifications, that they can then like and comment on together.
- Integrated with a Parse back-end to synchronize with a web client.
- Liaised with users to extract key behaviours in order to improve the product.

2014-2014 **Zzish** London, United Kingdom

Lead iOS developer

- Responsible for the development and refactoring of the Zzish iOS SDK.
- Implemented full unit-test coverage and provided comprehensive documentation and tutorials.
- Worked on several demo applications: Math Safari, XO Tic Tac Toe and Flovoco.
- Integrated with Java Spring REST API using JSON.
- Implemented custom webview based login that could be customised to client's needs, including token exchange.
- Interviewed several potential new hires and mentored a junior iOS developer.

Freelance iOS developer

- Created iOS applications for international clients whilst dealing with time zone constraints.
- Swiftly understood and worked with existing codebases to integrate bug fixes and new features.
- Completed full applications and guided clients to App Store release.
- Apps worked on: Huntzz (update), OneDegree, Safety Tracker (adhoc release)

2012-2012 The App Business

London, United Kingdom

iOS developer intern

- Contributed to iOS apps such as Unilever Investor Centre and SoundBites, and oversaw the TalkTalk sponsorship project for ITV's XFactor 2012.
- Collaborated within small dynamic teams of around five people within the Scrum agile development framework; participated in daily standups, project reviews and sprint planning.
- Built a custom view controller that connected with both YouTube and a custom API for displaying video content.
- Created drawing and labelling annotations for their in-house iOS PDF viewer library.
- Solely responsible for delivery of application sections given tight sprint deadlines.

education

2010-2014 Master of Engineering

The University of Warwick

Computer Science

Graduated with First Class Honours.

Thesis: Enhancing safety-critical message dissemination in vehicular wireless networks. Published

2008-2010 **A-Levels**

Queen Elizabeth Sixth Form College, Darlington

Computing (A), Mathematics (B), Physics (B), AS History (A), AS Extended Project (B)

projects

2012-2013 **Student property portal**

Developed a Ruby on Rails application that automatically scrapes student housing information from all student estate agents in Leamington Spa. It combines each property with an Internet speed, Virgin Media availability and crime statistics and allowed students to make more informed decisions when finding a student property.

2011-2012 **Firework Flare**

http://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/firework-flare/id513766705

A combination of Fruit Ninja and an old PlayStation 2 launch title Fantavision, Firework Flare lets you orchestrate your own firework show by chaining together fireworks of different colours. Developed with cocos2d, a 2D game engine, and custom designed in Photoshop. Firework Flare required real concern for performance given that it was developed for the iPad and iPad 2.

References available upon request.